BALLARD M. INGRAM

312-543-0074

ballardingram@outlook.com

For years, I've developed my skills and qualifications through diverse experiences that build meaningful relationships, challenge my Leadership approach, and keep my focus on personal career growth. As industries develop with innovation and client demands I adapt quickly and create new resources for those that will use them to exceed expectations in their daily responsibilities and goals.

Experience

Process Workflow Manager

bolt Access Austin, TX 06/2020 - 02/2022

- Develop processes through partnerships with Underwriting, Customer Service, Sales, and Agency Managers aimed at improved efficiency of processing role responsibilities and daily schedules. This covers an organization of over 100 employees within Distribution.
- · Oversee workflow and call queues; assist with open case management; reassign and resolve escalations; and ensure Platform Queues are within SLA.
- Aggregate and analyze data used in the company Staffing Model. For Finance, Executive Teams, and Front-End Managers.
- Redesign the new hire training for Service improving onboarding time and production.

Service Manager

bolt Access Austin, TX 02/2019 - 02/2022

- Coach and Develop a team of thirty (30) licensed and unlicensed Property & Casualty Insurance Representative responsible for inbound calls.
- Foster a company culture that rallies the team toward similar goals by sharing metrics, KPIs, and improving processes for the sake of the team's efficiency.
- Produce a weekly scorecard to Executives that analyzes the previous week's production, quality, and rankings for the entire staff. Expanded this into monthly, quarterly, and yearly.
- Investigate and resolve corporate escalations from inbound calls, our website, and corporate emails. This involved creating processes to prevent controllable losses.

Retention Supervisor

Charter Communications Austin, TX 07/2018 - 02/2019

- Lead a team of retention representatives with high sales goals. Provided coaching, support, and ongoing training passed down by corporate.
- Upsell additional products and meet weekly and monthly sales goals.
- Resolve corporate escalations.

Retail Banking CSC Manager HomeStreet Bank Federal Way, WA

12/2016 - 07/2018

- Report call center statistics to the Executive Committee and Board maintaining above average Key Performance Indicators.
- Partner with Operations Support, Electronic Banking, Wires and Payment Processing, Loan Servicing, Branches, and District Managers to improve communication with the Call Center and customers by innovating new ways to guickly relay important information.
- · Prevent controllable losses by rewriting clear procedures, improving authentication, and working closely with agents to ensure we are meeting the customer needs.
- Complete eight (8) to ten (10) Call Assessment Forms per agent per month with the assistance of two (2) Supervisors. Each CAF Scorecard is designed to provide comprehensive coaching and a clear understanding of areas that need improvement.

Professional Skills

Dependability, adaptability, and earning credibility through integrity are my primary motivators when entering a new role. I find that direct reports seek out support, resources, and education, but rarely obtain it from their leaders. To change this, I've developed new tools and methods that adjust to different learning styles. In my experience, this has empowered my direct reports and Leadership peers to stay involved, engaged, and dedicated. Here are the systems that I am proficient in:

Adobe Prepare and Suite AMS Avaya Bill.com Cisco Softphone Clearview ClickUP

Currency Teller DAT – Digital Admin Tool Excel Macros **EZlynx** FIS Cards FIS IBS Insight Five9

iOS and Android Software Lotus Notes LiveOps MadCap OKM Payleap Power BI

Salesforce **Sharepoint Forms Mapping** Snaglt **Tableau** TestMoz Verint Zendesk

License

NPN – 19190400 Property & Casualty Resident State - Texas AL - 3000591984 AZ - 19190400 CA - 0N03866 CO - 608781 CT - 2641944 FL - W585081 GA - 3275765 IL - 19190400 IN - 3451390 MD - 3000579530 MI - 19190400 MO - 8479412 NC - 19190400 NJ - 3000568642 NY - PC-1550518 OH - 1245497 PA - 898980 SC - 19190400 TX - 2413144 VA - 1128537 WA - 1019948

Education

University of Texas Austin
Full Stack Bootcamp
Web Development
01/27/2022 - 07/14/2022
Graduating Soon!

Lehman High School High School Diploma Kyle, TX 08/2005 – 05/2007 *Graduated!*

Software Skills

In the last six (6) months I've been an 'old dog learning new tricks,' sort of. My journey to become a full stack developer started with my years of professional experience. I've worked with a variety of teams that all had one-flaw. Access to efficient and helpful resources. I've used all of the free resources available to me to make something that would help. A 'wiki' of sorts. I knew in order to scale this idea I would have to learn how to create software from the ground up. Starting with a blank VS Code and an idea. I am very excited to have joined an amazing community of critical thinkers such as myself. Here are the software skills I am proficient in:

HTML

Git Bulma Javascript Node Handlebars **PWA** GraphQL **CSS Bootstrap** Tailwind API **SQL** MongoDB React Apache Oauth Stripe API Express.JS

References

Contact information available upon request for all references.

B. Stopa Professional Reference Manager – Peer bolt Access C. Bea Professional Reference Manager – Peer bolt Access P. Varvell
Professional Reference
Supervisor – Direct Report
HomeStreet Bank